<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Sara Asgari</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sara Asgari</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From High School to Higher Education: Is Recreational Marijuana a Consumption Amenity for US College Students?</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/1/</guid><description>This paper examines the effects of recreational marijuana legalization (RML) on US college enrollment. Using difference-in-differences and event study methods, I find RML increases first-time enrollments by up to 9%, particularly out-of-state enrollments, without affecting degree completion rates. The impact is strongest for non-selective public colleges in early-adopting states. RML does not appear to influence college prices, quality, or in-state enrollment.</description></item><item><title>Dollars and Degrees: The Asymmetric Impact of State Appropriations on STEM and Non-STEM Fields</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/2/</guid><description>This paper examines how recreational marijuana legalization (RML) affects first-time college enrollment in the US using a unique college-level dataset and various estimation methods such as difference-in-differences, event study, and synthetic controls.</description></item><item><title>What is the Role of Sports at Elite Universities in the US?</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/3/</guid><description>This paper analyzes the population of athletes at all Division I NCAA institutions. Using publicly available data from the US Department of Education, the NCAA, and institutions&amp;rsquo; athletic rosters, we document several novel facts. We show that elite institutions enroll more athletes and field more varsity teams than even the largest public institutions, despite having drastically smaller student bodies. Finally, we analyze the effect of a hypothetical policy that would restrict student athletes at each universities to be less than a certain fraction of the overall student body.</description></item><item><title>Balancing Tuition and Fees: Do Growing College Fees Affect Student Outcomes?</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/4/</guid><description>I investigate how state-imposed tuition caps and freezes affect the relationship between tuition and fees at US public universities. A one-dollar increase in tuition leads to a 45 to 62 cent reduction in fees, as institutions raise or introduce new fees when tuition increases are limited. Using an instrumental variable approach, I find that while the fee share has a negligible effect on first-time college enrollment, it significantly reduces STEM major completions. A 10 percentage point increase in fee share results in a 1.6 percent decrease in STEM major awards.</description></item><item><title>What Spurs Production and Innovation in the Vaccine Industry? Insights from Policy Interventions in the US</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/5/</guid><description>This paper investigates the impact of supply- and demand-side policy interventions on firms&amp;#39; output and innovation. Leveraging a unique dataset on vaccine production and development, we evaluate the effectiveness of a tort reform, a supply-side policy intervention that reduces vaccine manufacturers&amp;#39; product liability, and a demand-side policy intervention, the expansion of Medicare coverage of select vaccine products.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist Hugo Template for Academic Websites</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d5/</guid><description>This template produces a minimalist academic website with Hugo.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist LaTeX Commands to Write Math</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d3/</guid><description>This collection of minimalist commands make it easy to write mathematical expressions with LaTeX.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist LaTeX Template for Academic Papers</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d2/</guid><description>This template produces a minimalist academic paper with LaTeX.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist LaTeX Template for Academic Presentations</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/d1/</guid><description>This template produces a minimalist academic presentation with LaTeX Beamer.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/resume/c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/resume/c1/</guid><description>Download Resume View Resume This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: Download PDF.</description></item><item><title>1. Elements of Statistics (ECON 2843)</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c1/</guid><description>This is an introductory statistics course, which surveys basic statistical techniques with particular emphasis on business and economic applications. The learning objective of this course is to improve students&amp;#39; analytical skills in understanding and employing the descriptive and inferential statistics.</description></item><item><title>2. Elements of Statistics (ECON 2843)</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c2/</guid><description>This is an introductory statistics course, which surveys basic statistical techniques with particular emphasis on business and economic applications. The learning objective of this course is to improve students&amp;#39; analytical skills in understanding and employing the descriptive and inferential statistics.</description></item><item><title>3. Principles of Microeconomics (ECON 1123)</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c3/</guid><description>The objective of this course is to introduce students to basic microeconomic concepts and prepare them for future economic classes. By the end of this class, students should be able to understand microeconomic theory and its applications, prepare and understand basic equilibrium graphs, relate economic topics to real world situations, and explain economic principles.</description></item><item><title>4. Principles of Macroeconomics (ECON 1113)</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/c4/</guid><description>The objective of this course is to introduce students to basic Macroeconomics concepts and prepare them for future economic classes. By the end of this class, students should be able to (1) understand and explain basic macroeconomic concepts and basic elements of how the economy in the US is structured, (2) apply their understanding of economics to current events, and (3) be able to distinguish between correct and incorrect economic logic</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/location/</guid><description>My mailing and office addresses at the University of Oklahoma, Norman.</description></item><item><title>Office Hours</title><link>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/officehours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://saraasgarigouraj.github.io/officehours/</guid><description>Schedule and location for my office hours at the University of California, Santa Cruz.</description></item></channel></rss>